Insurance companies have taken significant steps at the policy level and
we have seen a tremendous recovery in all types of insurance stocks.
So, we are currently in the
insurance company spotlight. The
management of ICICI Lombard is joining us
and Sanjay Dutta ji, in
fact, he is the head of the underwriting and claims
division, which is the most important
area for any insurance company.
He is joining us for a special conversation.
Thank you very much sir.
Welcome to Eating and Sudesh.
Inflation remains a major concern for
insurance companies,
so the premium growth will gradually
go above 2%,
2.1% is your estimate. What is your view on that and what do
you think about pricing across
products? Will the sector recover? Is the
price currently playing a
huge role in product pricing?
So, our product, I mean, suppose
someone gets sick, he gets
treated, the cost
of treatment keeps
increasing over the years because [
music] it is
quite large, I mean normal.  The reason is
bigger than impression. So
this is the reason why when
we do product pricing, its
price keeps
increasing so that all
our other costs, our
distribution costs, our own costs, are
kept to a minimum so that
we can maintain that as much as possible. And this means that there is
some relief for the customers as well if they
increase it. There are
changes in the product also
so that the product is suitable for the customer. The
second thing is that we also try to
reduce the entire healthcare system, for example, any motor tax repairing system in the motor,
so that the cost is
less than it should be. And we keep trying to keep any
repairing cost in healthcare or motor, to a minimum
so that our influence on this
product is minimal.
Absolutely, Mr. Dutta, in the going forward
insurance reforms, P funding will be
seen increasing because
IRDAI has increased the cap limit
and now P has
also seen getting the freedom to become promoters.
How much difference will this make to the total growth of the sector,
how much?  This will have an impact on the sector in the future.
[Music]
Capital is
very
important because if we
cover more risks,
we need capital to cover it. And
if we
get capital from the sector, from the PM, from
other normal sources,
or we
generate it ourselves, these are very important aspects so that the
insurance company can
sell it. The
biggest thing is that the insurance regulator
monitors us. Our
solvency is increasing. To keep the outstanding amount,
we will need applications.
[Music]
More capital,
more contracts
are very important reforms so that as we move forward,
many more insurance companies will
come. The insurance companies that are already in the sector
also need to
increase their penetration, for that too we need capital.
Looking at all this, it is very important for us
that capital keeps coming and we
make insurance. A
person takes life insurance only once
because there is only one life, but they
take vehicles again and again. New vehicle
models are coming, so the new motor insurance must be
growing very fast.  Please
tell us about this segment, at what
speed is this segment growing on a month to month basis, it is
visible that for the last
one or two years, the motor vehicle growth has been stagnant due to the valuable chip
and now the production
is increasing and consumer demand is also increasing, so there is
old demand as well as new demand is also increasing,
so we feel that the demand in all the
voter card segments, private two
wheelers will definitely increase and right now the
economic activity is picking up, so the
demand for commercial vehicles is also
picking up, so
in the overall motor vehicle segment, new vehicles,
which
means to a large extent,
make up for the low growth of the last two years,
thank you for talking to us today and
for sharing your views with us on demand and pricing friends, look forward